Previously on the show.
上集說到
The goats ended up in Balloon City during a storm,
眾羊誤闖風暴中的氣球城
and ran into Sparky who was a wanted figure.
偶遇被通緝的沸羊羊
After failing to escape the storm,
在逃離風暴失敗後
they found that General Balloon, who was trying to capture Sparky,
才發現通緝沸羊羊的球將軍
was actually Sparky's good friend.
其實是沸羊羊的好朋友
What will happen to the goats while staying in Balloon City?
留在氣球城的小羊 會發生怎樣的故事呢？
"Flying Island: The Sky Adventure: The Beam That Makes You Strong And Tough."
《奇幻天空島之》
You're all Sparky's friends.
你們都是沸羊羊的朋友
Let me be a good host and show you our delicacies!
讓我好好招待你們 給你們嚐嚐我們的美食吧
Wow, delicacies!
哇，美食！
This contains our most famous cuisine.
這裡面裝的是我們最有名的料理
Isn't our food delicious?
我們的美食好吃吧
There is no food! It's just air!
什麼美食，都是空氣
They are balloons,
因為他們是氣球
so they only eat air.
所以他們的食物只有空氣啊
What do we eat then?
那我們吃什麼？
Don't worry.
不用擔心
Rubbish bin?
垃圾桶？
They don't eat food.
他們不吃食物
So food caught in the storm
所以這些捲進來的食物
would be thrown into the bin as rubbish.
都會被當做垃圾扔進垃圾桶
Wow! There's so much delicious food!
哇！這麼多好吃的
Sigh, you goats don't know how to appreciate our delicacies.
哎，你們這些小羊 都不會欣賞我們的美食
Go in.
進去吧
Wolnie?
紅紅？
Wolffy? You're finally here.
灰太狼？你終於來了
Why are you guys here?
你們怎麼在這裡啊？
That day...
那天…
Wolffy!
灰太狼？
Wolnie, Willie! It was so dangerous! Are you hurt?
紅紅、小灰灰，那麼危險 你們沒受傷吧？
-Dad. -We are fine now.
-爸爸 -我們已經沒事了
I'm glad you're both safe.
你們平安就好了
Wolffy.
灰太狼
Wolnie.
紅紅
I'm really touched at the sight of your family reunion.
見到你們一家團聚真是太感人了
But Sirius is too dangerous.
可是你們的天狼號太危險了
We've confiscated it...
我們沒收了
You confiscated Sirius?
沒收天狼號？
Also, you destroyed our houses.
還有，你們破壞了我們的房子
We have captured you so that you will clear the rubbish for us
抓你回來，就是讓你幫我們清理垃圾
as compensation.
作為賠償的
You confiscated Sirius
沒收我的天狼號
and you still expect me to clear your rubbish?
還想讓我幫你們清理垃圾？
I, Wolffy, won't--
本大王才不會…
Won't what?
不會什麼？
Won't reject the idea.
不會拒絕的
Weslie, what new functions does the Magic Train have?
喜羊羊 你說嘻哈號現在有什麼新功能啊？
We just need to put our palm mark on the new Magic Train
現在的嘻哈號 只要按上我們各自的手印
to activate our respective abilities.
就可以啟動各自不同的能力
That amazing?
這麼神奇？
Let's give it a try then.
那讓我們快去試一試啊
Is this my seat?
這就是我的座位嗎？
Come on, try activating it with your palm mark.
快點試一試啟動手印吧
Let's see what the function is.
快嘗試一下有什麼功能吧
Start!
啟動！
Good afternoon, goats.
午安啊，小羊們
General Balloon!
球將軍！
I saw you come aboard Magic Train, so I came to take a look.
我看到你們跑上嘻哈號 就特意過來看看
You didn't do anything dangerous, right?
你們沒做什麼危險的事情吧？
Of course not.
沒有
That's good then. I'm leaving.
那就好，我走了
Be careful, okay?
你們一定要注意安全啊
General Balloon blocked our view just now.
剛才球將軍擋著了
We can't tell what the beam from Magic Train does.
根本就看不出嘻哈號 射出的光線有什麼用
And this button isn't lit up anymore.
而且，這個按鈕也不亮了
That means the skill is cooling off.
那是技能正在冷卻
Let's try again later.
我們等一下再試試吧
We're done!
掃完了！
Son, there's still a lot more rubbish to clear.
兒子，前面還有很多垃圾呢
Why's there so much rubbish here?
這裡怎麼那麼多的垃圾啊？
The storm is to blame.
你要怪就怪這個風暴吧
Like all this stuff, we came from Earth.
我們和這些東西一樣來自陸地
After being sucked into the storm,
這個風暴把我們捲進來以後
seeing that we can fly,
因為我們氣球會飛
we gathered together to build Balloon City.
所以，我們聚攏在一起 建立了這個氣球城
For safety purposes, we built high walls.
為了安全，我們建起了高高的圍牆
But there're still many things that get blown into the city.
但仍有很多雜物從城的上空飛來
If there's too much rubbish in the city, we'll be pulled down to the ground.
如果城裡堆積的垃圾太多
So, our duty is to clear the rubbish in the city at all times.
所以我們的職責是 隨時把城內的垃圾清理掉
I can't stand this weight either.
我現在也承受不了這種重量了
Wolffy!
灰太狼！
Wolnie!
紅紅！
It has cooled off.
技能冷卻時間過了
Let's try aiming it at the apple.
我們試一下對著蘋果發射吧
Good idea.
好主意
I found a fridge full of food.
居然被我撿到了一冰箱的食物
Start!
啟動！
Look, everybody. I found a fridge full of food!
大家快看，我撿到了一冰箱的食物
Paddi! Move out of the way!
懶羊羊！快走開！
What a big harvest!
真是大豐收！
Nothing happened to me?
我沒事？
Why has the fridge shrunk?
冰箱怎麼變小了？
It has also become very light.
而且還變得好輕啊
It doesn't hurt at all.
一點都不痛
What exactly is going on?
這到底是怎麼回事啊？
It turns out that Sparky's skill is to make something strong and tough.
原來沸羊羊的功能 是讓物體變得強壯又堅硬啊
I see!
原來如此！
I'm back to normal.
打回原形了
So it only lasts for ten minutes.
原來技能只能維持十分鐘啊
It's impossible to clear all the rubbish!
這怎麼可能打掃得完啊？
I must find Sirius soon and take Wolnie and Willie away.
我要趕緊找到天狼號 帶紅紅和小灰灰走
Where are you going?
走去哪？
I'm going to sweep every corner of this city.
走遍這個城的每一個角落去掃地
I must try and find out where Sirius is.
要想辦法問天狼號的下落才行啊
Balloon City is so small. Where do you hide big objects?
氣球城這麼小 你們怎麼藏那麼大件的東西呢？
Why should I tell you?
為什麼要告訴你啊？
It's because you don't know, right?
是因為你不知道吧？
Of course I know!
我當然知道了！
This is the giant goods warehouse. Big enough, huh?
這是巨型物品倉庫，夠大了吧？
I don't mean this.
不是這個
I want to go to the place where vehicles are kept.
我想去的是放交通工具的地方
I see.
原來是那裡啊
Garage, boatyard, hangar.
汽車庫，這是遊艇庫、飛機庫
There are so many planes.
原來那麼多的飛機啊
I can take Wolnie away from here.
我可以帶上紅紅離開這裡
But these are only models.
不過呢，這些都是模型
I guess I must be explicit.
看來我只能直接一點了
Actually, I want to know where Sirius is.
其實我只想知道天狼號在哪啊
Turn left at the intersection ahead and you'll see it.
前面那個路口左轉就是
Wow! There's a flying saucer!
哇，有飛碟！
That isn't a flying saucer!
哪是飛碟啊？
It's clearly a huge rock!
明明是塊大石頭嘛
Emergency! A huge meteorite will hit Balloon City within ten minutes.
緊急報導！ 十分鐘內將有巨大的隕石撞向氣球城
Please take necessary precautions to avoid the impact.
請大家做好防砸措施
What should we do?
怎麼辦啊？
Calm down, everybody!
大家冷靜！
Don't we have the beam that makes one strong and tough?
我們不是有強硬射線嗎？
We can just use it to turn one of us into a giant and knock the meteorite away.
用它把我們變成巨人 打飛巨石不就好了嗎？
Then I must do it. I have the experience.
那只能我來了，我有經驗
Si... rius?
天狼…號？
This isn't Sirius!
不是這個天狼號啊
So Magic Train is parked here.
原來嘻哈號停在這裡了
Isn't that...
那個是…
Just let me save everybody.
就讓我來拯救大家吧
A goat?
小羊？
Let me catch a few goats before locating Sirius.
那找到天狼號之前
Oh, no. Wolffy got hit by the strong beam.
糟了！強硬射線射中了灰太狼
He's strong and tough now.
他現在又堅硬又強壯啊
He's gonna eat us all.
我們全部要被他吃掉了
I've become strong and tough.
我變得又堅硬又強壯了
Now I'm powerful.
我現在變得這麼厲害
Nothing can stop me from catching the goats now.
就沒有什麼可以阻止我抓羊了
Wolffy!
灰太狼！
Wolffy, you've been smirking for the past nine and a half minutes.
灰太狼你剛才傻笑了9分30秒
Your ability will be gone in thirty seconds.
你的能力還有30秒就消失了
Thirty seconds is enough time for me to catch you all.
30秒抓你們就足夠了
Wolffy? Is this the time to think about catching goats?
灰太狼？這個時候還想著抓羊
Look up!
你看看天空
What?
什麼天空啊？
Wolffy, while you're still strong and tough, knock the rock away.
灰太狼，趁你現在還是強硬狀態 快把石頭打飛啊
The meteorite will hit the city in ten seconds.
還有十秒隕石就來了
Wolffy, go for it.
灰太狼加油
Dad, go for it.
爸爸加油
Go for it...
加油…
That's easier said than done.
有些油不是你們說加就能加的啊
There are four more seconds! Three!
還有四秒！三…
Go for it!
加油…
-Two! -Go for it!
-二… -加油…
One!
一！
He did it!
成功了…
Great!
好啊！
Sparky's ability is awesome.
沸羊羊的能力太厲害了
Let's find a way to break through the storm now.
那我們接下來想辦法走出風暴吧
Before we break through the storm, let's escape from Wolffy first!
在走出風暴之前，先逃脫灰太狼啊
I helped you get rid of the rock.
本大王幫你們打走了石頭
Let me eat you! Stop!
你們快給我吃吧，別跑！
Does it really last for only ten minutes?
真的只有十分鐘嗎？
Let's cheer for the hero!
讓我們為英雄高呼
Wolffy, thank you for saving us. What a happy day!
灰太狼，謝謝你救了我們
We must celebrate.
今天這麼高興 我們一定要好好慶祝一下
You've destroyed our houses!
我們的房子！
Sorry, we'll continue with tidying up!
對不起，我們會繼續努力掃地的
TO BE CONTINUED 2759 DAYS FROM SETTING SAIL
（未完待續 距離啟航還剩2759天）